Guide to the Martin Shubik Papers, 1947-2009 and undated, bulk 1960-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings and Research Series, 1951-2009 and undated, (59 boxes)
  - Writings by Shubik Subseries, 1952-2008 and undated, (59 boxes)
    - Other Papers Subseries, 1951-2005 and undated, (6 boxes)
      - Three Essays on Decentralized Trade comments by M. Shubik, undated
      - Three Simple Experimental Games (working paper), 1992
      - Towards an Economic Dynamics with Many Generations with Arthur, W. (typed manuscript), undated
      - Towards an Economic Dynamics (written draft, manuscript), undated
      - A Trading Model to Avoid Tatonnement Metaphysics (galley), 1975
      - A Two Party System with Government, Bureaucracy, and Mass Voting (draft), 1982, 2 folders
      - Uncertainty and an Optimal Bankruptcy Law (draft, revisions), 1984
      - A Unified Model of Quantity, Price, and Price-Quantity Duopoly (draft), undated (Box 111)
      - Update of the Aggressive-Conservative Investor (typed manuscript), 2005
      - The Uses of Teaching Games in Game Theory Classes... (reprint), 2002
      - The Value of Money and Network Constraint with Bak, P. (notes), undated
      - The Variation of Stock Prices with Bak, P., Maslov, S., Karatzas, I., Sudderth, W., and Geanakoplos, J. (drafts, manuscript), 1996
      - Varying the Money Supply (drafts, revisions, working papers, notes, correspondence), (4 folders)
      - Who Gets What, How? (typed manuscripts), 2005
      - Unidentified draft: biography of Shubik (manuscript, notes), undated
      - Unidentified draft: culture and commerce, undated
      - Unidentified draft: Econometrica (abstract), undated
      - Unidentified manuscript: gaming, 1971
      - Unidentified manuscript: latex economics (paper, correspondence), 1997
    - Research Subseries, (2 boxes)
      Contains extensive research notes for works and subjects not readily connected with a specific work or title. Topics touch upon matters such gaming, auctions, and bidding. The series also includes Shubik's various bibliographies, both of select publications of his own work and of research topics. The series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
      - Artificial Intelligence, gaming theory, etc. (bibliographies), undated (Box 111)
      - Auctions, bidding (notes, clippings, manuscript in unknown hand, translation of Talamanca work), 1960s
      - Bibliography, various economists, undated
      - Bibliography, Shubik (notes, articles), 1971
      - Bibliography, Shubik, 1973
      - Bibliography, select publications, 1989
      - Bibliography, select publications, 1998
      - Bibliography, select publications, undated
      - Bidding (correspondence) (Box 112)
      - Bidding, simple models, (notes), undated
      - Business and regulation (notes), undated
      - World financial crises, world debt (notes), undated
      - Games, undated
      - Gaming (unidentified notes), undated
      - Gaming and simulation bibliography, undated
      - Historical approaches to production models (table), 1980s
      - Imputation, two-person bargaining (proof, galley), 1950 and undated
      - Mathematical finance models (notes), 2000s
      - Multiple equilibria (notes), undated
      - Nuclear stability, strategy (notes, correspondence), undated
      - Problems of pareto optimal surface by Frisch, H. (notes), 1969
      - Production in economic models (notes), 1999
      - Socio-economic and international simulations (notes), 1964 and c. 1979
      - Switching in a market with taxation and transaction costs (notes), undated
      - T.E.M.P.E.R (notes, review), 1967
      - Truancy (article by unidentified author), undated
      - URI (notes), undated
  - Writings by Others Subseries, 1955-2007 and undated, (3 boxes)
    Subseries includes academic works by authors such as L. Shapley, A. Sanghvi, R. Selten and S. Sahi. The files often include signed reprints, notes, working papers, articles, and advertisements. Also included is a book manuscript by R. Nelson and S. Winter. The subseries is arranged alphabetically by author.
    - Aker, J. and Anderson, J., Operations Research in the Warsaw Pact Armed Forces, 1974 (Box 112)
    - Amir, R., Aumann, R., Peck, J., and Wooders, M., Games and Economic Behavior in Honor of M. Shubik, 2004
    - Anderson, R., Quick Response Equilibrium, 1983
    - Averch, H., Evaluating Models: trends and prospects, 1972
    - Beder, M., A Futures and Options Market for Agricultural Products in Mexico, 1993
    - Bouchard, J. P. and Sornette, D., Derivatives Trading, 1996
    - Cohen, J., Can Human Irrationality Be Experimentally Demonstrated?, 1981
    - Brams, S., Davis, M., and Straffin, P., The Geometry of the Arms Race, 1979
    - Edwards, W., Lindman, H., and Savage, L., Bayesian Statistical Inference... (signed copy), 1963
    - Filar, J., The Completely Mixed Single-Controlling Stochastic Game, 1983
    - Filar, J., The Travelling Inspector Model, 1983
    - Filar, J. and Raghavan, T. E. S., A Matrix Game Solution of the Single-controller Stochastic Game, undated
    - De Finetti, B., La Teoria dei Giochi, 1963
    - Frank, M., The Braess Paradox, 1981
    - Fudenberg, D. and Maskin, E., The Folk Theorem in Repeated Games..., 1984
    - Goldhamer, H., Social Mobility (signed reprint), 1968
    - Gordon, J., Shareholder Initiative and Social Choice... (signed reprint), 1991
    - Klipstein, D., The Contributions of Edsel Murphy..., 1969
    - Kantorovich, L., Dynamic Models of Scientific-technical Progress (signed reprint), 1974
    - Kreps, D. and Wilson, R., Sequential Equilibria, 1982 (Box 113)
    - Markov, M., Science and the Responsibility of Scientists (signed reprint), 1975
    - Milnor, J. and Shapley, L., On Games of Survival, 1955
    - Nelson, R. and Winter, S., An Evolutionary Theory of Economic Capabilities and Behavior (manuscript), 1982, (4 folders)
    - Powers, M., Sin, Short-selling, Taxes, Bubbles and the Price of Shares, (undated)
    - Rosenthal, R., Discussion of Lloyd Shapley's Noncooperative General Exchange, undated
    - Sahi, S., The Noncooperative Equilibria of a Trading Economy..., 1987
    - Sanghvi, A., The Asympotic Behavior of some Sequential Games, 1973 (Box 114)
    - Selten, R., The Chain Store Paradox, 1974
    - Simon, J., Puig, C. and Aschoff, J., A Duopoly Simulation and Richer Theory, 1973
    - Stahl, I., The Use of Operational Gaming..., 1980
    - Stern, G. Karreman, A., unidentified book, undated
    - Trockel, W., The Chain Store Paradox Revisited, 1984
    - Whitman, M., Merger Proxy Statements and Exchange Prospectuses, 1973
    - Wold, H., Mergers of Economics and Philosophy of Science (signed reprint), 1969
    - Unidentified author, The Geoffrey Hazard Short Course in Economics, undated
    - Various authors, Omni (superiority of female brain, x-ray holograms, consciousness, and the split brain), 1983